# **ALEXANDRA FALLER**

# **WEB DEVELOPER**

# **SKILLS**

- · HTML/5
- · CSS/3
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- · React.is
- - Express.js
    - SCSS
    - Bootstrap
    - MongoDb
      Cit/Cithub
    - Git/Github



# EXPERIENCE

## **Expert Agent, Frome**

February 2012 – September 2014

Web Developer

- Coding websites for clients using a variety of coding languages and applications
- Liaising and communicating with clients to arrange website needs and desires using non-jargon to help explain things in terms a non-technical customer can understand
- Carrying out customisations within a timely manner to suit the customer
- Adding bespoke customisation to Joomla templates using ¡Query and PHP
- Integrating Joomla system with the powering from the Expert Agent system
- Designing banners and customised elements in Photoshop & Illustrator and applying them to webpage

#### The Virtual Forge, Bath August 2011 – February 2012

Junior Developer

- Translating PSD Designs into an interactive web user experience using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Using the jQuery & MooTools framework to add dynamic functionality to webpages
- Testing sites in multiple Mac and Windows browsers to give a cross platform look and feel for any user
- Coding registration and video portal pages using PHP and MySQL
- Adapting websites for mobile and tablets to enable users to keep the same interactivity of a desktop site
- Working closely with the designer to translate ideas from the client into a functional user experience
- Carrying out SEO and marketing techniques as well as integration of social media into the pages
- Working to strict deadlines to ensure launch of sites and pages are on target

## **PROFILE**

As a highly motivated Web Developer with over 15 years coding experience, I am looking to resume my professional career in the workplace after dedicating the last 7 years to raising my family whilst free-lancing.

With good organization and communication skills, I am punctual, committed, and can be relied upon. I enjoy challenges and learning new skills. I have worked on multiple freelance projects and use resources including Udemy and YouTube to keep my skills up to date and follow web trends.

I would now like to utilise my skills and experience I have gained to undertake a new challenge.

# **EDUCATION**

Huntington University, Huntington, Indiana, USA

January 2008 – January 2010

BSc Level

- 3.4 GPA Computer Science
  - JAVA
  - (++
  - VB with ASP.NET
  - C#
- Computer Architecture and Assembler Language

Swansea Metropolitan University September 2005 – July 2007

HND

• Distinction - Computing

# CONTACT

#### Phone:

07496581539

#### Email:

Alex@alexfaller.uk

#### **Portfolio:**

alexfaller.uk

#### Github:

github.com/A13X4ND7A

#### Freelance Web Development

### October 2010 - August 2011

- Speaking with customers and discussing their requirements for the project
- Using a range of languages to create dynamic sites such as Javascript, JQuery, PHP & MySQL
- Update and maintain existing sites
- Carry out SEO techniques
- Ensuring all tasks are completed on time

## Bay View Systems, Swansea

#### August 2010 - October 2010

Web Developer

- 12 Week work placement developing websites
- Created dynamic HTML templates from image mock-ups using CSS, HTML and JQuery
- Converted HTML templates to PHP pages for the in-house CMS system
- Added new functionality in PHP pages for search functions, news pages, events etc for both the front-end site and back-end CMS
  - Responsible for carrying out tasks in a timely manner.

### Technology Services, Huntington University, USA February 2009 – October 2009

IT Support

- Resolving student and staff laptop problems and logging them into the university system
- Identifying and solving networking issues and faults
- Maintain critical Anti-Virus servers, backup and disaster recovery systems to ensure minimal disruption to essential services in the event of a virus outbreak or a systems failure
- Desktop support for around 600 PCs, 500 staff and 3000 student accounts, based across the campus
- Responsible for creating own work list, prioritising and carrying out the work to the highest standards

## Reusser Design, Roanoke, USA

May 2009 - August 2009

Web Developer Intern

- Summer intern role supporting the team with client projects
- Responsible for website updates and maintenance for clients
- Followed W3C standards to create rich websites for clients
- · Used Wordpress and created templates to enable clients to update their own content
- Translated Adobe Photoshop PSD into Web Templates

## INTERESTS

I love spending time with my family, we often game together and enjoy exploring our local beauty spots. I also enjoy keeping fit and ran the Cardiff Half Marathon for Mind Charity. I am an avid crocheter, mostly making amigurumi.

In my spare time, I enjoy learning new web languages and like to practice by creating projects for myself which can be seen on github.

I hold a full clean driving license.

# REFERENCES

References are available upon request.